All right. Well, let's bridge this the
last step. We are here printing out the
entire object and we actually just want
to print this advice. Um, so let's go
in. So this object that we're printing
out has a key called slip. And that slip
key has another object inside of it that
has a key called advice. So if we want
to access it here, instead of
console.logging JSON.data, I'll
console.log JSON.data.slip. slip.vice.
And down here, instead of console
logging result, I'll console log
result.slip.advice.
And if I save that here, we get the
number of vampires in the average home
is directly proportional to the amount
of garlic bread in the fridge. Um, and
we get that twice. Um, which means we
are able to successfully go out, access
an API, and use it in our code. So, what
APIs are there? Well, there's a lot.
Most of the internet runs this way. Um,
so here, um, if you come to github.com/
uh, public API list API lists, um, you
will, and I'll put the link in the
description. Um, you can see a list of
APIs that do a lot of things. So,
there's this catfax API where you could
get cat facts. Um, you could get random
dog pictures, random fox pictures. Um,
you could learn things about rescue
groups. Um, that's if you're into
animals, if you're into anime, if you're
into anti-malware. Some of these are
pretty cool. Um,
you can, uh, Google safe browse. Like,
there is so many cool things out there
that someone has built an API so you can
access it. I believe up here Google
calendar has an API. That means you
could write yourself an app using the
JavaScript you've learned and the fetch
function that you've learned that will
integrate directly with your Google
calendar, which is pretty freaking cool.
Um, and just look at all of the APIs
that are now available to you now that
you know how to access data over the
internet using JavaScript. Like the sky
is the limit here. I mean, it just keeps
going. Um, so hopefully that is helpful.
And um right now I know I've only taught
you get requests. I'm going to put a
little bit of a pin in that. Leave you
on a bit of a cliffhanger and we are
going to stop at get requests for now
and then in future videos we'll talk
about the other requests and probably a
little bit of an easier way to do the
other requests. But again, just wanted
to show you how many resources there are
out there um that you can use. Like I
said, it just keeps going. If there's
something you want to build, there is
probably an API out there to help you
build it.
Oh, I should probably also define what
API is. API stands for application
programming interface and it is
something that makes your job easier. So
the function that we used called fetch
is actually called the fetch API. It is
an application programming interface,
meaning it's something that you use your
code for that makes your job easier. So
rather than having to go write all the
code to go out to the internet and grab
stuff, it makes your job easier. These
are REST APIs, meaning they follow the
framework where you make get um post,
put, and delete requests to them. And
they all follow that format. And um so
you can come check these out. And that's
it for this